All Fur One. One Fur All.
Open Season is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Roger Allers.
Boog, a domesticated 900lb.
Grizzly bear finds himself stranded in the woods 3 days before Open Season.
Forced to rely on Elliot, a fast-talking mule deer, the two form an unlikely friendship and must
quickly rally other forest animals if they are to form a rag-tag army against the hunters.
Boog (voice), played by Martin Lawrence.
Elliot (voice), played by Ashton Kutcher.
Shaw (voice), played by Gary Sinise.
Beth (voice), played by Debra Messing.
McSquizzy (voice), played by Billy Connolly.
Bobbie (voice), played by Georgia Engel.
Open Season is a 2006 American animated adventure comedy film directed by Jill Culton
and Roger Allers and written by Nat Mauldin, Steve Bencich, and Ron J.
Produced by Sony Pictures Animation, it features the voices of Martin
Lawrence, Ashton Kutcher, Gary Sinise, and Debra Messing.
The film follows Boog, a domesticated grizzly bear, who is let go into the woods, and teams up with a
one-antlered mule deer named Elliot to return to his old home before open season starts.
Open Season premiered at the Greek Theatre on September 25, 2006, and was released in
theaters in the United States on September 29 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
$201 million against an $85 million budget.
The first in the Open Season film series, it was followed by Open Season 2
(2008), Open Season 3 (2010), and Open Season: Scared Silly (2015).
A video game based on the film was released, and a television series,
Open Season: Call of Nature, was released in 2023.
The film explores themes of hunter, chase, bunny, garage, mountain.
The tone is lighthearted.